<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Mark S. Handcock</title><link>https:handcock.github.io/</link><atom:link href="https:handcock.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><description>Mark S. Handcock</description><generator>Source Themes Academic (https://sourcethemes.com/academic/)</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>2022</copyright><lastBuildDate>Tue, 31 May 2022 08:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><image><url>https:handcock.github.io/images/logo_hua85a92e198a1ba12ec186662f58b214f_99585_300x300_fit_lanczos_3.png</url><title>Mark S. Handcock</title><link>https:handcock.github.io/</link></image><item><title>STATS 102A: Introduction to Computational Statistics with R</title><link>https:handcock.github.io/teaching/102a/</link><pubDate>Thu, 24 Nov 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https:handcock.github.io/teaching/102a/</guid><description>&lt;p>This course is an introduction to computational statistics through numerical
methods and computationally intensive methods for statistical problems. Topics
include statistical graphics, root finding, simulation, randomization testing,
and bootstrapping. Covers intermediate to advanced programming with R.&lt;/p>
&lt;!-- The Bruin Learn course page is [here](https://bruinlearn.ucla.edu/courses/79280/). -->
&lt;!-- A detailed description of the class is available [here](https://drive.google.com/file/d/1Sn3TagfjAdrQ6x9jcEmwD91GZEZN7T81/view?usp=sharing/). -->
&lt;h3 id="motivation-and-synopsis">Motivation and Synopsis&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>During the twentieth century, the development of statistical computing played a crucial facilitating role for the growth of the statistics
discipline and the adoption of statistical methods within the scientiﬁc community and beyond. In the twenty-ﬁrst
century digital age, the amounts of data available for statistical analysis has grown tremendously, yielding new opportunities for
statistical computing, as well as new challenges. Statistical computing constitutes an important part of a statistics
education, and is highly valuable for statisticians in both academia and industry.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This course is designed to provide the upper-division statistics student with the fundamentals of statistical computing, particularly
through use of the language R.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The course is thematically split into two parts. The ﬁst part will focus on learning the tools and the necessary skills to perform
computational statistics. Students will learn intermediate to advanced R programming and usage of some of its functions
and packages. The student will learn how to develop functions and packages for the management, pre-processing and analysis of statistical
data. The second part of the class will focus on some foundational methods in computational statistics. This
includes numerical methods such as root ﬁnding, numeric integration, and mathematical optimization. It will continue on to cover the
generation of random variables, simulation, and Monte Carlo methods to answer statistical questions.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The computer is the scientific laboratory of the statistician. It plays the same role for the statistical research as the traditional
laboratories play for physics and chemistry researchers. As such this course should allow the student to develop a degree
of comfort and competence "in the lab.”&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The primary purpose of this course is to provide students with a common set of core knowledge about statistical computing computing for
their class work and research. The course will have an applied focus on tools. The course will involve the practical
application of the ideas of statistical computing and their implementation through statistical software, particularly &lt;span
class="s3">R&lt;/span>.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="syllabus-of-the-course">Syllabus of the Course&lt;/h3>
&lt;table style="border-collapse: collapse; width: 63.9406%;" border="1">
&lt;tbody>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td style="width: 12.3397%;">&lt;strong>Lecture&lt;/strong>&lt;/td>
&lt;td style="width: 87.5549%;">&lt;strong>&amp;nbsp;Topics&lt;/strong>&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td style="width: 12.3397%;">1&lt;/td>
&lt;td style="width: 87.5549%;">&lt;span>Introduction, the R language and eco-system&lt;/span>&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td style="width: 12.3397%;">2&lt;/td>
&lt;td style="width: 87.5549%;">&lt;span>Data structures and their management&lt;/span>&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td style="width: 12.3397%;">3&lt;/td>
&lt;td style="width: 87.5549%;">&lt;span>R programming and writing functions&lt;/span>&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td style="width: 12.3397%;">4&lt;/td>
&lt;td style="width: 87.5549%;">&lt;span>Importing data, web scraping, manipulating data with tidyr and dpyr&lt;/span>&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td style="width: 12.3397%;">5&lt;/td>
&lt;td style="width: 87.5549%;">Visualization and graphics (ggplot2)&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td style="width: 12.3397%;">6&lt;/td>
&lt;td style="width: 87.5549%;">Numerical methods: floating point arithmetic, root finding&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td style="width: 12.3397%;">7&lt;/td>
&lt;td style="width: 87.5549%;">Numerical methods: basic optimization&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td style="width: 12.3397%;">8&lt;/td>
&lt;td style="width: 87.5549%;">Random numbers, random variables, and simulation in R&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td style="width: 12.3397%;">9&lt;/td>
&lt;td style="width: 87.5549%;">Randomization tests, permutation tests and bootstrapping&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;td style="width: 12.3397%;">10&lt;/td>
&lt;td style="width: 87.5549%;">Additional topics: Monte Carlo-integration, kernel density estimation&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;/tbody>
&lt;/table>
&lt;p>
&lt;p>A detailed description of the class is available &lt;a
href="https://drive.google.com/file/d/0B9xtdS-e9O_kc1RCUGhuWGhqZEE/view?usp=sharing">here&lt;/a>.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>STATS 184: Societal Impacts of Data</title><link>https:handcock.github.io/teaching/184/</link><pubDate>Mon, 03 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https:handcock.github.io/teaching/184/</guid><description>&lt;p>This course considers the impacts that data collected today have upon individuals and society. Rapid increase in scale and types of data
collected has impacted commerce and society in new ways. Consideration of economic, social and ethical, legal and political impacts of data,
especially that collected on human behavior. Topics include privacy and data protection, intellectual property and confidentiality, sample
selection and algorithms, equality and anti-discrimination.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The Bruin Learn course page is
&lt;a href="https://bruinlearn.ucla.edu/courses/79280/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">here&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;!-- A detailed description of the class is available [here](https://drive.google.com/file/d/1Sn3TagfjAdrQ6x9jcEmwD91GZEZN7T81/view?usp=sharing/). -->
&lt;h3 id="motivation-and-synopsis">Motivation and Synopsis&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>During the twentieth century, the development of statistical computing played a crucial facilitating role for the growth of the statistics
discipline and the adoption of statistical methods. In the twenty-first century digital age, the amounts of data available for statistical
analysis has grown tremendously, yielding new opportunities , as well as new challenges.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This course considers the impacts that the data collected today have upon individuals and society. The rapid increase in the scale and types of
data collected has impacted commerce and society in new ways. In this course we consider the economic, social and ethical, legal and political
impacts of data, especially that collected on human behavior. Particular topics will be privacy and data protection, intellectual property and
confidentiality, sample selection and algorithms, equality and anti-discrimination.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This course is intended to provide students sociological, psychological and economic lenses to explore how our increasingly digital lifestyle
changes institutions and social relations. These lenses are then used to guide data scientists in their work.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The course has various parts:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>We&amp;rsquo;ll consider what data is and the growth of Big Data.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>We will consider the role data play in the broader information context and how that context influences the data we collect and the related statistical issues.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>We will consider statistical techniques to improve privacy and data protection, confidentiality, sample selection and algorithms, equality and anti-discrimination.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h3 id="syllabus-of-the-course">Syllabus of the Course&lt;/h3>
&lt;table style="border-collapse: collapse; width: 63.9406%;" border="1">
&lt;tbody>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td style="width: 12.3397%;">&lt;strong>Lecture&lt;/strong>&lt;/td>
&lt;td style="width: 87.5549%;">&lt;strong>&amp;nbsp;Topics&lt;/strong>&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td style="width: 12.3397%;">1&lt;/td>
&lt;td style="width: 87.5549%;">Introduction: &lt;span>What, really, is Data?&lt;/span>&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td style="width: 12.3397%;">2&lt;/td>
&lt;td style="width: 87.5549%;">&lt;span>Contextualizing Data&lt;/span>&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td style="width: 12.3397%;">3&lt;/td>
&lt;td style="width: 87.5549%;">&lt;span>Small Data and Big Data&lt;/span>&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td style="width: 12.3397%;">4&lt;/td>
&lt;td style="width: 87.5549%;">Datafication and its Implications&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td style="width: 12.3397%;">5&lt;/td>
&lt;td style="width: 87.5549%;">Statistical methods to preserve privacy&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td style="width: 12.3397%;">6&lt;/td>
&lt;td style="width: 87.5549%;">Sample selection and algorithms&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td style="width: 12.3397%;">7&lt;/td>
&lt;td style="width: 87.5549%;">
&lt;p>Equality and anti-discrimination&lt;/p>
&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td style="width: 12.3397%;">8&lt;/td>
&lt;td style="width: 87.5549%;">Intellectual and Personal Property&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;td style="width: 12.3397%;">9&lt;/td>
&lt;td style="width: 87.5549%;">Additional topics&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;/tbody>
&lt;/table></description></item><item><title>STATS 202B: Matrix Algebra and Optimization</title><link>https:handcock.github.io/teaching/202b/</link><pubDate>Tue, 19 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https:handcock.github.io/teaching/202b/</guid><description>&lt;p>This course is a survey of computational methods that are especially useful for statistical analysis, with implementations in statistical package R. Topics include matrix analysis, multivariate regression, principal component analysis, multivariate analysis, and deterministic optimization methods.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The Bruin Learn course page is
&lt;a href="https://bruinlearn.ucla.edu/courses/79284/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">here&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>A detailed description of the class is available
&lt;a href="https://drive.google.com/file/d/1Sn3TagfjAdrQ6x9jcEmwD91GZEZN7T81/view?usp=sharing/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">here&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="motivation-and-synopsis">Motivation and Synopsis&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>During the twentieth century, the development of statistical computing played a crucial facilitating role for the growth of the statistics discipline and the adoption of statistical methods within the scientiﬁc community and beyond. In the twenty-ﬁrst century digital age, the amounts of data available for statistical analysis has grown tremendously, yielding new opportunities for statistical computing, as well as new challenges. Statistical computing constitutes an important part of a statistics education, and is highly valuable for statisticians in both academia and industry.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This course is an introduction computational methods that are useful for statistical analysis, with implementations in the statistical package &lt;span class="s3">R&lt;/span>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Computational methods are essential to both understand and implement modern statistical ideas. Often the computation methods are a translation of the statistical methods into another language, one that computer understand. In this class we will consider this process for key statistical models and techniques. These include multivariate regression, principal component analysis, and multivariate analysis. In doing so, we study the core mathematical and numerical ideas that make this possible including matrix analysis and deterministic optimization methods.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The course has various parts:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>We&amp;rsquo;ll do some &lt;em>matrix algebra&lt;/em> (not linear algebra), emphasizing what is available in &lt;span class="s3">R&lt;/span>.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>We apply the matrix algebra to &lt;em>multivariate data analysis&lt;/em>, in particular to regression, principal component analysis, canonical analysis, correspondence analysis.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>We discuss &lt;em>optimization methods. These will be mainly deterministic but also stochastic methods&lt;/em>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>We finally apply both optimization and linear algebra to discuss statistical techniques such as multidimensional scaling, independent component analysis, tomography, and generalized mixed linear models. Well, maybe not all.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>The primary purpose of this course is to provide students with a common set of core knowledge about statistical computing computing for their class work and research. The course will have an applied focus on tools. The course will involve the practical application of the ideas of statistical computing and their implementation through statistical software, particularly &lt;span class="s3">R&lt;/span>.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>STATS 202C: Monte Carlo Methods for Optimization</title><link>https:handcock.github.io/teaching/202c/</link><pubDate>Sun, 03 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https:handcock.github.io/teaching/202c/</guid><description>&lt;p>This course is a survey of Monte Carlo methods and numerical integration. Importance and rejection sampling. Sequential importance sampling.
Markov chain Monte Carlo (MCMC) sampling techniques, with emphasis on Gibbs samplers and Metropolis/Hastings. Simulated annealing. Exact
sampling with coupling from past. Permutation testing and bootstrap confidence intervals.&lt;/p>
&lt;!--- (The Bruin Learn course page is [here](https://bruinlearn.ucla.edu/courses/79284/). -->
&lt;p>A detailed description of the class is available
&lt;a href="https://drive.google.com/file/d/1w0yeax2DYoKjAbyN3p6OFSds69K8NRcn/view?usp=sharing" target="_blank" rel="noopener">here&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="motivation-and-synopsis">Motivation and Synopsis&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>During the twentieth century, the development of statistical computing played a crucial facilitating role for the growth of the statistics
discipline and the adoption of statistical methods within the scientiﬁc community and beyond. In the twenty-ﬁrst century digital age, the
amounts of data available for statistical analysis has grown tremendously, yielding new opportunities for statistical computing, as well as new
challenges. Statistical computing constitutes an important part of a statistics education, and is highly valuable for statisticians in both
academia and industry.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This graduate level course introduces Monte Carlo methods for simulation, optimization, estimation, learning and complex landscape
visualization, including: Importance sampling; Sequential importance sampling; Markov chain Monte Carlo (MCMC) sampling techniques including
Gibbs samplers, Metropolis/Hastings and various improvements; Simulated annealing; Exact sampling techniques; Convergence analysis; Data
augmentation; Cluster sampling, such as Swendsen-Wang and SW-cuts; Hamiltonian and Langevin Monte Carlo; Equi-energy and multi-domain sampler;
and Techniques for mapping complex energy landscapes&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The primary purpose of this course is to provide students with a common set of core knowledge about statistical computing computing for their
class work and research. The course will have an applied focus on tools. The course will involve the practical application of the ideas of
statistical computing and their implementation through statistical software, particularly R.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Prerequisites&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Stat 202B: Matrix Algebra and Optimization.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>People who didn’t take 202B before may still take this class as long as they have background on matrix algebra, probability theory, and programming skills. To do this attend the first classes and we can assess if this is advisable.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul></description></item><item><title>STATS C216/C116: Social Statistics</title><link>https:handcock.github.io/teaching/c216/</link><pubDate>Sun, 03 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https:handcock.github.io/teaching/c216/</guid><description>&lt;p>This course is designed for social sciences graduate students and advanced undergraduate students seeking training in data issues and methods
employed in social sciences.&lt;/p>
&lt;!--- (The Bruin Learn course page is [here](https://bruinlearn.ucla.edu/courses/79284/). -->
&lt;p>A detailed description of the class is available
&lt;a href="https://drive.google.com/file/d/1uT2NyUyFROvAB2DG4R5-OuoP3dsQ32sb/view?usp=sharing" target="_blank" rel="noopener">here&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="motivation-and-synopsis">Motivation and Synopsis&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Statistics C116/C216 is a second course in social statistics and will
&lt;em>focus on Bayesian statistical analysis&lt;/em>. It will cover the principles
of Bayesian statistics, Bayesian data analysis and modeling. In
particular it will develop the ideas in the context of linear
regression, its non-linear generalizations, and hierarchical models.
While the idea and principles are general, all applications and models
will be chosen from those most relevant to the social sciences.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This course is designed for graduate students majoring in Statistics,
the Social Sciences and advanced undergraduate students who are planning
to attend graduate school.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This course is most appropriate for student seeking additional training
in the application of Bayesian statistics to data and are looking for an
introductory course that advances rapidly. The ultimate goal is to equip
students with the analytical and programming skills necessary to address
social statistics problems within the Bayesian paradigm based on current
data and technologies.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The course has various perspectives:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li> It focuses on conceptual understanding of the Bayesian statistics.&lt;/li>
&lt;li> It focuses on conceptual understanding of the the primary models used in social statistics.&lt;/li>
&lt;li> It involves the analysis of real-data.&lt;/li>
&lt;li> It involves implementing the methods using freely available software.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>The course will involve the practical application of the ideas of
statistical computing and their implementation through statistical
software, particularly [R]{.s3}. As statistical computation is essential
for many of the modeling approaches, expertise will need to be
developed.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>STATS 218: Statistical Analysis of Networks</title><link>https:handcock.github.io/teaching/218/</link><pubDate>Sat, 03 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https:handcock.github.io/teaching/218/</guid><description>&lt;p>This course is a introduction to the analysis of social structure, conceived in terms of social relationships. Major concepts of social network
theory and mathematical representation of social concepts such as role and position. Use of graphical representations of network information.&lt;/p>
&lt;!--- (The Bruin Learn course page is [here](https://bruinlearn.ucla.edu/courses/79284/). -->
&lt;p>A detailed description of the class is available
&lt;a href="https://drive.google.com/file/d/1NU65AGnpAOuH_tgJsrFVzlFKfoDikL3b/view?usp=sharing" target="_blank" rel="noopener">here&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="motivation-and-synopsis">Motivation and Synopsis&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>This course is an introduction to the analysis of social structure,
conceived in terms of social relationships.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Social structure is conceptualized as a system of social relations
tieing distinct social entities to one another. Social network theory is
the attempt to represent the structure in social relations via networks.
It is then a theory pertaining to types of observable social spaces and
their relation to individual and group
behavior.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Observations on the social relations are of two forms:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>individual level information on the social entities&lt;/li>
&lt;li>relational data on pairs of entities&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>While both forms are important for the study of social relations,
social network theory recognizes fundamental role of the relational
information. It is based on the premise that social context is an
important determinant of individual behavior. It seeks to understand
individual and group behavior in terms of relational information rather
than as solely the aggregation of individual
characteristics.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The focus of the course are modern methods for the statistical analysis
of social networks. The course covers the major concepts of social
network theory and the mathematical representation of social concepts
such as &amp;ldquo;role&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;position&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Visualization plays a central in social network analysis. With the
development of high speed computing and graphical display tools,
visualization has become a flexible and powerful tool in the exploration
of social relations. Graphics exploit the power of our visual senses to
convey information in a direct way. In this course we will emphasize the
use of graphical representations of network information as much as
possible.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Sampling Hard-to-Reach Populations</title><link>https:handcock.github.io/talk/ssc-icmic22/</link><pubDate>Tue, 31 May 2022 08:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https:handcock.github.io/talk/ssc-icmic22/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Tool for tracking all-cause mortality and estimating excess mortality to support the COVID-19 pandemic response</title><link>https:handcock.github.io/publication/who-acm-calc/</link><pubDate>Wed, 25 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https:handcock.github.io/publication/who-acm-calc/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Data Theory in the World Seminar: How Data Drives Business Decisions</title><link>https:handcock.github.io/talk/intheworld2205/</link><pubDate>Tue, 24 May 2022 17:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https:handcock.github.io/talk/intheworld2205/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Migrating my website to Hugo + Academic</title><link>https:handcock.github.io/post/migrating/</link><pubDate>Wed, 20 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https:handcock.github.io/post/migrating/</guid><description>&lt;p>After many years with a hand written website in HTML, I moved to using the
&lt;a href="https://gohugo.io/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Hugo&lt;/a> framework with the
&lt;a href="https://sourcethemes.com/academic/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Academic theme&lt;/a>.
The motivation for this is the work of
&lt;a href="http://www.statslab.cam.ac.uk/~qz280/post/migrating/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Qingyuan Zhao&lt;/a> who deserved the credit for both creating the template and also publishing it so that others can benefit from it. Thank you, Qingyuan Zhao!&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>CCPR</title><link>https:handcock.github.io/research/ccpr/</link><pubDate>Tue, 19 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https:handcock.github.io/research/ccpr/</guid><description>&lt;p>I am an affiliate of the
&lt;a href="http://www.ccpr.ucla.edu/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">California Center for Population Research&lt;/a> at UCLA.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>A New Record Minimum for Antarctic Sea Ice</title><link>https:handcock.github.io/publication/nature-min/</link><pubDate>Thu, 10 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https:handcock.github.io/publication/nature-min/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Comparing the real-world performance of exponential-family random graph models and latent order logistic models for social network analysis</title><link>https:handcock.github.io/publication/ensemble-lolog/</link><pubDate>Fri, 28 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https:handcock.github.io/publication/ensemble-lolog/</guid><description/></item><item><title>A Regime Shift in Seasonal Total Antarctic Sea Ice Extent in the Twentieth Century</title><link>https:handcock.github.io/publication/nature-regime-shift/</link><pubDate>Mon, 10 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https:handcock.github.io/publication/nature-regime-shift/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Tracking all cause of death and estimating excess mortality during the COVID-19 pandemic: statistical and computational tools</title><link>https:handcock.github.io/talk/whotag22/</link><pubDate>Thu, 09 Dec 2021 16:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https:handcock.github.io/talk/whotag22/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Eighteen-year record of circum-Antarctic landfast-sea-ice distribution allows detailed baseline characterisation and reveals trends and variability</title><link>https:handcock.github.io/publication/fast-ice/</link><pubDate>Wed, 03 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https:handcock.github.io/publication/fast-ice/</guid><description/></item><item><title>A Note on 'Sequential Neighborhood Effects' by Hicks et al. (2018)</title><link>https:handcock.github.io/publication/nghbd-note/</link><pubDate>Thu, 01 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https:handcock.github.io/publication/nghbd-note/</guid><description/></item><item><title>An Assessment of the Temporal Variability in the Annual Cycle of Daily Antarctic Sea Ice in the NCAR Community Earth System Model, Version 2: A Comparison of the Historical Runs with Observations</title><link>https:handcock.github.io/publication/assess-cesm2/</link><pubDate>Sat, 17 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https:handcock.github.io/publication/assess-cesm2/</guid><description/></item><item><title>COVID-19</title><link>https:handcock.github.io/project/covid-19/</link><pubDate>Fri, 24 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https:handcock.github.io/project/covid-19/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Modeling the annual cycle of daily Antarctic sea ice extent</title><link>https:handcock.github.io/publication/annual-cycle/</link><pubDate>Thu, 02 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https:handcock.github.io/publication/annual-cycle/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Modeling wildfire ignition origins in southern California using linear network point processes</title><link>https:handcock.github.io/publication/wildfire/</link><pubDate>Sun, 01 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https:handcock.github.io/publication/wildfire/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Population Size Estimation Using Multiple Respondent-Driven Sampling Surveys</title><link>https:handcock.github.io/publication/pse2/</link><pubDate>Sat, 07 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https:handcock.github.io/publication/pse2/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Bayesian inference for finite populations under spatial process settings</title><link>https:handcock.github.io/publication/bayes-finite-pop/</link><pubDate>Wed, 25 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https:handcock.github.io/publication/bayes-finite-pop/</guid><description/></item><item><title>A Simulation-Based Framework for Assessing the Feasibility of Respondent-Driven Sampling for Estimating Characteristics in Populations of Lesbian, Gay and Bisexual Older Adults</title><link>https:handcock.github.io/publication/griffin/</link><pubDate>Tue, 13 Nov 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https:handcock.github.io/publication/griffin/</guid><description/></item><item><title>A Conditional Empirical Likelihood Based Method for Model Parameter Estimation from Complex survey Datasets</title><link>https:handcock.github.io/publication/emplik/</link><pubDate>Tue, 06 Mar 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https:handcock.github.io/publication/emplik/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Methods for Inference from Respondent-Driven Sampling Data</title><link>https:handcock.github.io/publication/annrevrds/</link><pubDate>Thu, 01 Mar 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https:handcock.github.io/publication/annrevrds/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Sequential Neighborhood Effects: The Effect of Long-Term Exposure to Concentrated Disadvantage on Children's Reading and Mathematical Skills</title><link>https:handcock.github.io/publication/nghbd/</link><pubDate>Thu, 30 Nov 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https:handcock.github.io/publication/nghbd/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Evaluating Variance Estimators for Respondent‐Driven Sampling</title><link>https:handcock.github.io/publication/evalvarrds/</link><pubDate>Thu, 17 Aug 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https:handcock.github.io/publication/evalvarrds/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Removing Phase Transitions from Gibbs Measures</title><link>https:handcock.github.io/publication/phasetapering/</link><pubDate>Thu, 20 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https:handcock.github.io/publication/phasetapering/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Analysis of Networks with Missing Data with Application to the National Longitudinal Study of Adolescent Health</title><link>https:handcock.github.io/publication/netmiss/</link><pubDate>Thu, 29 Sep 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https:handcock.github.io/publication/netmiss/</guid><description/></item><item><title>On the Concept of Snowball Sampling</title><link>https:handcock.github.io/publication/onsnowball/</link><pubDate>Wed, 19 Oct 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https:handcock.github.io/publication/onsnowball/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Bayesian estimation of hispanic fertility hazards from survey and population data</title><link>https:handcock.github.io/publication/bayesdemo/</link><pubDate>Sun, 01 Feb 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https:handcock.github.io/publication/bayesdemo/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Model-based Assessment of the Impact of Missing Data on Inference for Networks</title><link>https:handcock.github.io/publication/cssswp_66/</link><pubDate>Thu, 07 Sep 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https:handcock.github.io/publication/cssswp_66/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Alleviating Linear Ecological Bias and Optimal Design with Subsample Data</title><link>https:handcock.github.io/publication/cssswp_51/</link><pubDate>Tue, 06 Sep 2005 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https:handcock.github.io/publication/cssswp_51/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Generalised Linear Models Incorporating Population Level Information: An Empirical Likelihood Based Approach</title><link>https:handcock.github.io/publication/cssswp_48/</link><pubDate>Thu, 05 May 2005 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https:handcock.github.io/publication/cssswp_48/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Model-Based Clustering for Social Networks</title><link>https:handcock.github.io/publication/cssswp_46/</link><pubDate>Wed, 27 Apr 2005 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https:handcock.github.io/publication/cssswp_46/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Inference in curved exponential family models for networks</title><link>https:handcock.github.io/publication/cssswp_43/</link><pubDate>Tue, 03 Aug 2004 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https:handcock.github.io/publication/cssswp_43/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Goodness of Fit of Social Network Models</title><link>https:handcock.github.io/publication/cssswp_47/</link><pubDate>Wed, 28 Apr 2004 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https:handcock.github.io/publication/cssswp_47/</guid><description/></item><item><title>New specifications for exponential random graph models</title><link>https:handcock.github.io/publication/cssswp_42/</link><pubDate>Fri, 23 Apr 2004 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https:handcock.github.io/publication/cssswp_42/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Positional Estimation Within a Latent Space Model for Networks</title><link>https:handcock.github.io/publication/cssswp_41/</link><pubDate>Fri, 09 Apr 2004 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https:handcock.github.io/publication/cssswp_41/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Assessing Degeneracy in Statistical Models of Social Networks</title><link>https:handcock.github.io/publication/cssswp_39/</link><pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 2003 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https:handcock.github.io/publication/cssswp_39/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Generalised Linear Models Incorporating Population Level Information: An Empirical Likelihood Based Approach</title><link>https:handcock.github.io/publication/cssswp_36/</link><pubDate>Tue, 23 Sep 2003 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https:handcock.github.io/publication/cssswp_36/</guid><description/></item><item><title>On 'Sexual contacts and epidemic thresholds,' models and inference for Sexual partnership distributions</title><link>https:handcock.github.io/publication/cssswp_31/</link><pubDate>Tue, 27 May 2003 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https:handcock.github.io/publication/cssswp_31/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Interval Estimates for Epidemic Thresholds in Two-Sex Network Models</title><link>https:handcock.github.io/publication/cssswp_44/</link><pubDate>Fri, 14 Mar 2003 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https:handcock.github.io/publication/cssswp_44/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Likelihood-Based Inference for Stochastic Models of Sexual Network Formation</title><link>https:handcock.github.io/publication/cssswp_29/</link><pubDate>Wed, 29 Jan 2003 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https:handcock.github.io/publication/cssswp_29/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Applying Relative Distribution Methods in R</title><link>https:handcock.github.io/publication/cssswp_27/</link><pubDate>Sun, 01 Dec 2002 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https:handcock.github.io/publication/cssswp_27/</guid><description/></item><item><title>An Assessment of Preferential Attachment as a Mechanism for Human Sexual Network Formation</title><link>https:handcock.github.io/publication/cssswp_23/</link><pubDate>Tue, 15 Oct 2002 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https:handcock.github.io/publication/cssswp_23/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Statistical Evidence Tells Tails of Human Sexual Contacts</title><link>https:handcock.github.io/publication/cssswp_21/</link><pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2002 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https:handcock.github.io/publication/cssswp_21/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Divergent Paths: Economic Mobility in the New American Labor Market</title><link>https:handcock.github.io/publication/book_divergent_paths/</link><pubDate>Thu, 21 Jun 2001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https:handcock.github.io/publication/book_divergent_paths/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Relative Distribution Methods in the Social Sciences</title><link>https:handcock.github.io/publication/book_reldist/</link><pubDate>Fri, 01 Oct 1999 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https:handcock.github.io/publication/book_reldist/</guid><description/></item><item><title>A Casebook for a First Course in Statistics and Data Analysis</title><link>https:handcock.github.io/publication/book_casebook/</link><pubDate>Tue, 25 Apr 1995 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https:handcock.github.io/publication/book_casebook/</guid><description/></item><item><title/><link>https:handcock.github.io/featured/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https:handcock.github.io/featured/</guid><description/></item></channel></rss>