<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="https://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Mark S. Handcock</title><link>https://HPMRG.github.io/</link><atom:link href="https://HPMRG.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><description>Mark S. Handcock</description><generator>Source Themes Academic (https://sourcethemes.com/academic/)</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>2022</copyright><lastBuildDate>Wed, 24 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><image><url>https://HPMRG.github.io/images/logo_hu7ac5a2aa8fa12518fd9ab7ceccb2a15e_77341_300x300_fit_lanczos_3.png</url><title>Mark S. Handcock</title><link>https://HPMRG.github.io/</link></image><item><title>STATS 102A: Introduction to Computational Statistics with R</title><link>https://HPMRG.github.io/teaching/102a/</link><pubDate>Thu, 24 Nov 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://HPMRG.github.io/teaching/102a/</guid><description>&lt;p>This course is an introduction to computational statistics through numerical
methods and computationally intensive methods for statistical problems. Topics
include statistical graphics, root finding, simulation, randomization testing,
and bootstrapping. Covers intermediate to advanced programming with R.&lt;/p>
&lt;!-- The Bruin Learn course page is [here](https://bruinlearn.ucla.edu/courses/79280/). -->
&lt;!-- A detailed description of the class is available [here](https://drive.google.com/file/d/1Sn3TagfjAdrQ6x9jcEmwD91GZEZN7T81/view?usp=sharing/). -->
&lt;h3 id="motivation-and-synopsis">Motivation and Synopsis&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>During the twentieth century, the development of statistical computing played a crucial facilitating role for the growth of the statistics
discipline and the adoption of statistical methods within the scientiﬁc community and beyond. In the twenty-ﬁrst
century digital age, the amounts of data available for statistical analysis has grown tremendously, yielding new opportunities for
statistical computing, as well as new challenges. Statistical computing constitutes an important part of a statistics
education, and is highly valuable for statisticians in both academia and industry.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This course is designed to provide the upper-division statistics student with the fundamentals of statistical computing, particularly
through use of the language R.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The course is thematically split into two parts. The ﬁst part will focus on learning the tools and the necessary skills to perform
computational statistics. Students will learn intermediate to advanced R programming and usage of some of its functions
and packages. The student will learn how to develop functions and packages for the management, pre-processing and analysis of statistical
data. The second part of the class will focus on some foundational methods in computational statistics. This
includes numerical methods such as root ﬁnding, numeric integration, and mathematical optimization. It will continue on to cover the
generation of random variables, simulation, and Monte Carlo methods to answer statistical questions.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The computer is the scientific laboratory of the statistician. It plays the same role for the statistical research as the traditional
laboratories play for physics and chemistry researchers. As such this course should allow the student to develop a degree
of comfort and competence "in the lab.”&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The primary purpose of this course is to provide students with a common set of core knowledge about statistical computing computing for
their class work and research. The course will have an applied focus on tools. The course will involve the practical
application of the ideas of statistical computing and their implementation through statistical software, particularly &lt;span
class="s3">R&lt;/span>.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="syllabus-of-the-course">Syllabus of the Course&lt;/h3>
&lt;table style="border-collapse: collapse; width: 63.9406%;" border="1">
&lt;tbody>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td style="width: 12.3397%;">&lt;strong>Lecture&lt;/strong>&lt;/td>
&lt;td style="width: 87.5549%;">&lt;strong>&amp;nbsp;Topics&lt;/strong>&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td style="width: 12.3397%;">1&lt;/td>
&lt;td style="width: 87.5549%;">&lt;span>Introduction, the R language and eco-system&lt;/span>&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td style="width: 12.3397%;">2&lt;/td>
&lt;td style="width: 87.5549%;">&lt;span>Data structures and their management&lt;/span>&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td style="width: 12.3397%;">3&lt;/td>
&lt;td style="width: 87.5549%;">&lt;span>R programming and writing functions&lt;/span>&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td style="width: 12.3397%;">4&lt;/td>
&lt;td style="width: 87.5549%;">&lt;span>Importing data, web scraping, manipulating data with tidyr and dpyr&lt;/span>&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td style="width: 12.3397%;">5&lt;/td>
&lt;td style="width: 87.5549%;">Visualization and graphics (ggplot2)&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td style="width: 12.3397%;">6&lt;/td>
&lt;td style="width: 87.5549%;">Numerical methods: floating point arithmetic, root finding&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td style="width: 12.3397%;">7&lt;/td>
&lt;td style="width: 87.5549%;">Numerical methods: basic optimization&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td style="width: 12.3397%;">8&lt;/td>
&lt;td style="width: 87.5549%;">Random numbers, random variables, and simulation in R&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td style="width: 12.3397%;">9&lt;/td>
&lt;td style="width: 87.5549%;">Randomization tests, permutation tests and bootstrapping&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;td style="width: 12.3397%;">10&lt;/td>
&lt;td style="width: 87.5549%;">Additional topics: Monte Carlo-integration, kernel density estimation&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;/tbody>
&lt;/table>
&lt;p>
&lt;p>A detailed description of the class is available &lt;a
href="https://drive.google.com/file/d/0B9xtdS-e9O_kc1RCUGhuWGhqZEE/view?usp=sharing">here&lt;/a>.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>STATS 184: Societal Impacts of Data</title><link>https://HPMRG.github.io/teaching/184/</link><pubDate>Mon, 03 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://HPMRG.github.io/teaching/184/</guid><description>&lt;p>This course considers the impacts that data collected today have upon individuals and society. Rapid increase in scale and types of data
collected has impacted commerce and society in new ways. Consideration of economic, social and ethical, legal and political impacts of data,
especially that collected on human behavior. Topics include privacy and data protection, intellectual property and confidentiality, sample
selection and algorithms, equality and anti-discrimination.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The Bruin Learn course page is
&lt;a href="https://bruinlearn.ucla.edu/courses/79280/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">here&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;!-- A detailed description of the class is available [here](https://drive.google.com/file/d/1Sn3TagfjAdrQ6x9jcEmwD91GZEZN7T81/view?usp=sharing/). -->
&lt;h3 id="motivation-and-synopsis">Motivation and Synopsis&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>During the twentieth century, the development of statistical computing played a crucial facilitating role for the growth of the statistics
discipline and the adoption of statistical methods. In the twenty-first century digital age, the amounts of data available for statistical
analysis has grown tremendously, yielding new opportunities , as well as new challenges.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This course considers the impacts that the data collected today have upon individuals and society. The rapid increase in the scale and types of
data collected has impacted commerce and society in new ways. In this course we consider the economic, social and ethical, legal and political
impacts of data, especially that collected on human behavior. Particular topics will be privacy and data protection, intellectual property and
confidentiality, sample selection and algorithms, equality and anti-discrimination.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This course is intended to provide students sociological, psychological and economic lenses to explore how our increasingly digital lifestyle
changes institutions and social relations. These lenses are then used to guide data scientists in their work.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The course has various parts:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>We&amp;rsquo;ll consider what data is and the growth of Big Data.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>We will consider the role data play in the broader information context and how that context influences the data we collect and the related statistical issues.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>We will consider statistical techniques to improve privacy and data protection, confidentiality, sample selection and algorithms, equality and anti-discrimination.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h3 id="syllabus-of-the-course">Syllabus of the Course&lt;/h3>
&lt;table style="border-collapse: collapse; width: 63.9406%;" border="1">
&lt;tbody>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td style="width: 12.3397%;">&lt;strong>Lecture&lt;/strong>&lt;/td>
&lt;td style="width: 87.5549%;">&lt;strong>&amp;nbsp;Topics&lt;/strong>&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td style="width: 12.3397%;">1&lt;/td>
&lt;td style="width: 87.5549%;">Introduction: &lt;span>What, really, is Data?&lt;/span>&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td style="width: 12.3397%;">2&lt;/td>
&lt;td style="width: 87.5549%;">&lt;span>Contextualizing Data&lt;/span>&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td style="width: 12.3397%;">3&lt;/td>
&lt;td style="width: 87.5549%;">&lt;span>Small Data and Big Data&lt;/span>&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td style="width: 12.3397%;">4&lt;/td>
&lt;td style="width: 87.5549%;">Datafication and its Implications&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td style="width: 12.3397%;">5&lt;/td>
&lt;td style="width: 87.5549%;">Statistical methods to preserve privacy&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td style="width: 12.3397%;">6&lt;/td>
&lt;td style="width: 87.5549%;">Sample selection and algorithms&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td style="width: 12.3397%;">7&lt;/td>
&lt;td style="width: 87.5549%;">
&lt;p>Equality and anti-discrimination&lt;/p>
&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td style="width: 12.3397%;">8&lt;/td>
&lt;td style="width: 87.5549%;">Intellectual and Personal Property&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;td style="width: 12.3397%;">9&lt;/td>
&lt;td style="width: 87.5549%;">Additional topics&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;/tbody>
&lt;/table></description></item><item><title>STATS 202B: Matrix Algebra and Optimization</title><link>https://HPMRG.github.io/teaching/202b/</link><pubDate>Tue, 19 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://HPMRG.github.io/teaching/202b/</guid><description>&lt;p>This course is a survey of computational methods that are especially useful for statistical analysis, with implementations in statistical package R. Topics include matrix analysis, multivariate regression, principal component analysis, multivariate analysis, and deterministic optimization methods.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The Bruin Learn course page is
&lt;a href="https://bruinlearn.ucla.edu/courses/79284/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">here&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>A detailed description of the class is available
&lt;a href="https://drive.google.com/file/d/1Sn3TagfjAdrQ6x9jcEmwD91GZEZN7T81/view?usp=sharing/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">here&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="motivation-and-synopsis">Motivation and Synopsis&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>During the twentieth century, the development of statistical computing played a crucial facilitating role for the growth of the statistics discipline and the adoption of statistical methods within the scientiﬁc community and beyond. In the twenty-ﬁrst century digital age, the amounts of data available for statistical analysis has grown tremendously, yielding new opportunities for statistical computing, as well as new challenges. Statistical computing constitutes an important part of a statistics education, and is highly valuable for statisticians in both academia and industry.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This course is an introduction computational methods that are useful for statistical analysis, with implementations in the statistical package &lt;span class="s3">R&lt;/span>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Computational methods are essential to both understand and implement modern statistical ideas. Often the computation methods are a translation of the statistical methods into another language, one that computer understand. In this class we will consider this process for key statistical models and techniques. These include multivariate regression, principal component analysis, and multivariate analysis. In doing so, we study the core mathematical and numerical ideas that make this possible including matrix analysis and deterministic optimization methods.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The course has various parts:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>We&amp;rsquo;ll do some &lt;em>matrix algebra&lt;/em> (not linear algebra), emphasizing what is available in &lt;span class="s3">R&lt;/span>.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>We apply the matrix algebra to &lt;em>multivariate data analysis&lt;/em>, in particular to regression, principal component analysis, canonical analysis, correspondence analysis.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>We discuss &lt;em>optimization methods. These will be mainly deterministic but also stochastic methods&lt;/em>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>We finally apply both optimization and linear algebra to discuss statistical techniques such as multidimensional scaling, independent component analysis, tomography, and generalized mixed linear models. Well, maybe not all.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>The primary purpose of this course is to provide students with a common set of core knowledge about statistical computing computing for their class work and research. The course will have an applied focus on tools. The course will involve the practical application of the ideas of statistical computing and their implementation through statistical software, particularly &lt;span class="s3">R&lt;/span>.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>STATS 202C: Monte Carlo Methods for Optimization</title><link>https://HPMRG.github.io/teaching/202c/</link><pubDate>Sun, 03 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://HPMRG.github.io/teaching/202c/</guid><description>&lt;p>This course is a survey of Monte Carlo methods and numerical integration. Importance and rejection sampling. Sequential importance sampling.
Markov chain Monte Carlo (MCMC) sampling techniques, with emphasis on Gibbs samplers and Metropolis/Hastings. Simulated annealing. Exact
sampling with coupling from past. Permutation testing and bootstrap confidence intervals.&lt;/p>
&lt;!--- (The Bruin Learn course page is [here](https://bruinlearn.ucla.edu/courses/79284/). -->
&lt;p>A detailed description of the class is available
&lt;a href="https://drive.google.com/file/d/1w0yeax2DYoKjAbyN3p6OFSds69K8NRcn/view?usp=sharing" target="_blank" rel="noopener">here&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="motivation-and-synopsis">Motivation and Synopsis&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>During the twentieth century, the development of statistical computing played a crucial facilitating role for the growth of the statistics
discipline and the adoption of statistical methods within the scientiﬁc community and beyond. In the twenty-ﬁrst century digital age, the
amounts of data available for statistical analysis has grown tremendously, yielding new opportunities for statistical computing, as well as new
challenges. Statistical computing constitutes an important part of a statistics education, and is highly valuable for statisticians in both
academia and industry.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This graduate level course introduces Monte Carlo methods for simulation, optimization, estimation, learning and complex landscape
visualization, including: Importance sampling; Sequential importance sampling; Markov chain Monte Carlo (MCMC) sampling techniques including
Gibbs samplers, Metropolis/Hastings and various improvements; Simulated annealing; Exact sampling techniques; Convergence analysis; Data
augmentation; Cluster sampling, such as Swendsen-Wang and SW-cuts; Hamiltonian and Langevin Monte Carlo; Equi-energy and multi-domain sampler;
and Techniques for mapping complex energy landscapes&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The primary purpose of this course is to provide students with a common set of core knowledge about statistical computing computing for their
class work and research. The course will have an applied focus on tools. The course will involve the practical application of the ideas of
statistical computing and their implementation through statistical software, particularly R.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Prerequisites&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Stat 202B: Matrix Algebra and Optimization.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>People who didn’t take 202B before may still take this class as long as they have background on matrix algebra, probability theory, and programming skills. To do this attend the first classes and we can assess if this is advisable.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul></description></item><item><title>STATS C216/C116: Social Statistics</title><link>https://HPMRG.github.io/teaching/c216/</link><pubDate>Sun, 03 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://HPMRG.github.io/teaching/c216/</guid><description>&lt;p>This course is designed for social sciences graduate students and advanced undergraduate students seeking training in data issues and methods
employed in social sciences.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The Bruin Learn course page is
&lt;a href="https://bruinlearn.ucla.edu/courses/143496/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">here&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>A detailed description of the class is available
&lt;a href="https://drive.google.com/file/d/1uT2NyUyFROvAB2DG4R5-OuoP3dsQ32sb/view?usp=sharing" target="_blank" rel="noopener">here&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="motivation-and-synopsis">Motivation and Synopsis&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Statistics C116/C216 is a second course in social statistics and will
&lt;em>focus on Bayesian statistical analysis&lt;/em>. It will cover the principles
of Bayesian statistics, Bayesian data analysis and modeling. In
particular it will develop the ideas in the context of linear
regression, its non-linear generalizations, and hierarchical models.
While the idea and principles are general, all applications and models
will be chosen from those most relevant to the social sciences.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This course is designed for graduate students majoring in Statistics,
the Social Sciences and advanced undergraduate students who are planning
to attend graduate school.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This course is most appropriate for student seeking additional training
in the application of Bayesian statistics to data and are looking for an
introductory course that advances rapidly. The ultimate goal is to equip
students with the analytical and programming skills necessary to address
social statistics problems within the Bayesian paradigm based on current
data and technologies.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The course has various perspectives:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li> It focuses on conceptual understanding of the Bayesian statistics.&lt;/li>
&lt;li> It focuses on conceptual understanding of the the primary models used in social statistics.&lt;/li>
&lt;li> It involves the analysis of real-data.&lt;/li>
&lt;li> It involves implementing the methods using freely available software.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>The course will involve the practical application of the ideas of
statistical computing and their implementation through statistical
software, particularly &lt;span class="s3">R&lt;/span>. As statistical computation is essential
for many of the modeling approaches, expertise will need to be
developed.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>STATS 218: Statistical Analysis of Networks</title><link>https://HPMRG.github.io/teaching/218/</link><pubDate>Sat, 03 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://HPMRG.github.io/teaching/218/</guid><description>&lt;p>This course is a introduction to the analysis of social structure, conceived in terms of social relationships. Major concepts of social network
theory and mathematical representation of social concepts such as role and position. Use of graphical representations of network information.&lt;/p>
&lt;!--- (The Bruin Learn course page is [here](https://bruinlearn.ucla.edu/courses/79284/). -->
&lt;p>A detailed description of the class is available
&lt;a href="https://drive.google.com/file/d/1NU65AGnpAOuH_tgJsrFVzlFKfoDikL3b/view?usp=sharing" target="_blank" rel="noopener">here&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="motivation-and-synopsis">Motivation and Synopsis&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>This course is an introduction to the analysis of social structure,
conceived in terms of social relationships.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Social structure is conceptualized as a system of social relations
tieing distinct social entities to one another. Social network theory is
the attempt to represent the structure in social relations via networks.
It is then a theory pertaining to types of observable social spaces and
their relation to individual and group
behavior.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Observations on the social relations are of two forms:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>individual level information on the social entities&lt;/li>
&lt;li>relational data on pairs of entities&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>While both forms are important for the study of social relations,
social network theory recognizes fundamental role of the relational
information. It is based on the premise that social context is an
important determinant of individual behavior. It seeks to understand
individual and group behavior in terms of relational information rather
than as solely the aggregation of individual
characteristics.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The focus of the course are modern methods for the statistical analysis
of social networks. The course covers the major concepts of social
network theory and the mathematical representation of social concepts
such as &amp;ldquo;role&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;position&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Visualization plays a central in social network analysis. With the
development of high speed computing and graphical display tools,
visualization has become a flexible and powerful tool in the exploration
of social relations. Graphics exploit the power of our visual senses to
convey information in a direct way. In this course we will emphasize the
use of graphical representations of network information as much as
possible.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title/><link>https://HPMRG.github.io/rds/</link><pubDate>Wed, 24 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://HPMRG.github.io/rds/</guid><description>&lt;img src="https://HPMRG.github.io/img/RDS_hl.png" align="left" width="250" height="250" style="padding:30px;" alt="RDS network"/>
&lt;h1 id="the-rds-package">The &lt;code>RDS&lt;/code> package&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>This is an R package for carrying out estimation with data collected using Respondent-Driven Sampling. This includes
Heckathorn&amp;rsquo;s RDS-I and RDS-II estimators as well as Gile&amp;rsquo;s Sequential Sampling estimator.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The package is part of the &amp;ldquo;RDS Analyst&amp;rdquo; suite of
packages for the analysis of respondent-driven sampling data.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The package was developed by the
&lt;a href="https://HPMRG.github.io" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Hard-to-Reach Population Methods Research Group (HPMRG)&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>See Gile and Handcock (2010)
&lt;a href="doi:10.1111/j.1467-9531.2010.01223.x">doi:10.1111/j.1467-9531.2010.01223.x&lt;/a> and Gile and
Handcock (2015)
&lt;a href="doi:10.1111/rssa.12091">doi:10.1111/rssa.12091&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;img src="https://HPMRG.github.io/img/fauxmadrona_recplot.jpeg" width = 900 alt="RDS banner"/>
&lt;h1 id="installation">Installation&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>The package is available on CRAN and can be installed using&lt;/p>
&lt;pre>&lt;code class="language-{r}">install.packages(&amp;quot;RDS&amp;quot;)
&lt;/code>&lt;/pre>
&lt;!-- To install the latest development version from github, the best way it to use git to create a local copy and install it as usual from there. If -->
&lt;!-- you just want to install it, you can also use: -->
&lt;!-- ```{r} -->
&lt;!-- # If devtools is not installed: -->
&lt;!-- # install.packages("devtools") -->
&lt;!-- -->
&lt;!-- devtools::install_github("HPMRG/RDS") -->
&lt;!-- ``` -->
&lt;h1 id="implementation">Implementation&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>Load package and example data&lt;/p>
&lt;pre>&lt;code>library(RDS)
data(fauxmadrona)
&lt;/code>&lt;/pre>
&lt;p>&lt;code>fauxmadrona&lt;/code> is a simulated RDS data set with no seed dependency, which is used to demonstrate RDS estimators. It has the format of an
&lt;code>rds.data.frame&lt;/code> and is a sample of size 500 with 10 seeds and 2 coupons from a population of size 1000. For the purpose of this example, we
will assume the population size is unknown and our goal is to estimate it.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>We can make a quick visualization of the recruitment chains, where the size of the node is proportional to the reported degree and the color
represents separate chains.&lt;/p>
&lt;pre>&lt;code class="language-{r}">reingold.tilford.plot(fauxmadrona,
vertex.label=NA,
vertex.size=&amp;quot;degree&amp;quot;,
show.legend=FALSE,
vertex.color=&amp;quot;seed&amp;quot;)
&lt;/code>&lt;/pre>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="reingold.tilford.png" alt="">&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="the-rdsssestimates-function">The &lt;code>RDS.SS.estimates&lt;/code> function&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>This function computes the sequential sampling (SS) prevalence estimates for a categorical variable or numeric
variable.
The confidence intervals are computed using a bootstrap procedure.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Here are the results for disease prevalence:&lt;/p>
&lt;pre>&lt;code class="language-{r}">RDS.SS.estimates(rds.data=fauxmadrona,outcome.variable=&amp;quot;disease&amp;quot;,N=1000)
&lt;/code>&lt;/pre>
&lt;pre>&lt;code>## Gile's SS Estimate for disease
## Estimate 95% Interval Design Effect Std. Error N
## disease 0.1946 ( 0.1676, 0.2216) 1.21 0.0138 500
## Total 500
## * Using population size estimate: 1000
&lt;/code>&lt;/pre>
&lt;h2 id="other-primary-functions">Other primary functions&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>These are the primary functions that users will call. They are detailed in the
&lt;a href="https://cran.r-project.org/web/packages/RDS/RDS.pdf" target="_blank" rel="noopener">manual&lt;/a>
with example &lt;code>R&lt;/code> code.&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;code>bottleneck.plot&lt;/code>: This function creates a bottleneck plot to help diagnose convergence for RDS estimators.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;code>convergence.plot&lt;/code>: This function creates diagnostic convergence plots for RDS estimators.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;code>cumulative.estimate&lt;/code>: Calculates estimates at each successive wave of the sampling process&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;code>differential.activity.estimates&lt;/code>: Computes the Differential Activity between groups&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;code>homophily.estimates&lt;/code>: This function computes an estimate of the population homophily and the recruitment homophily based on a categorical variable.`&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;code>LRT.trend.test&lt;/code>: Compute a test of trend in prevalences based on a likelihood-ratio statistic&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;code>MA.estimates&lt;/code>: This function computes the sequential sampling (MA) estimates for a categorical variable or numeric variable.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;code>plot.rds.data.frame&lt;/code>: Diagnostic plots for the RDS recruitment process&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;code>RDS.bootstrap.intervals&lt;/code>: This function computes an interval estimate for one or more categorical variables. It optionally uses attributes of the RDS data set to determine the type of estimator and type of uncertainty estimate to use.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;code>RDS.compare.proportions&lt;/code>: Compares the rates of two variables against one another`: This function computes an interval estimate for one or more categorical variables. It optionally uses attributes of the RDS data set to determine the type of estimator and type of uncertainty estimate to use.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;code>RDS.HCG.estimates&lt;/code>: Prevalence estimates based on Fellows&amp;rsquo; Homophily Configuration Graph model&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;code>RDS.I.estimates&lt;/code>: Prevalence estimates based on the RDS-I type estimates for a categorical variable. It is also referred to as the Salganik-Heckathorn estimator.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;code>RDS.II.estimates&lt;/code>: Prevalence estimates based on the RDS-II type estimates for a categorical variable. It is also referred to as the Salganik-Heckathorn estimator.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;code>RDS.SS.estimates&lt;/code>: Prevalence estimates based on the sequential sampling (SS) model for a categorical or numerical variable. It is also referred to as the Gile estimator.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>See the following papers for more information and examples:&lt;/p>
&lt;h4 id="statistical-methodology">Statistical Methodology&lt;/h4>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Gile, Krista J. 2011
&lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.1198/jasa.2011.ap09475" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Improved Inference for Respondent-Driven Sampling Data with Application to HIV Prevalence Estimation&lt;/a>, Journal of the American Statistical Association, 106, 135-146.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Gile, Krista J., Handcock, Mark S., 2010
&lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.1111/j.1467-9531.2010.01223.x" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Respondent-driven Sampling: An Assessment of Current
Methodology&lt;/a>, Sociological Methodology, 40, 285-327.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Gile, Krista J., Handcock, Mark S., 2011
&lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.1111/rssa.12091" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Network Model-Assisted Inference from Respondent-Driven Sampling
Data&lt;/a>, Journal of the Royal Statistical Society, A.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Salganik, M., Heckathorn, D. D., 2004. &amp;ldquo;Sampling and estimation in hidden populations using respondent-driven sampling.
Sociological Methodology 34, 193-239.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Volz, E., Heckathorn, D., 2008. Probability based estimation theory for Respondent Driven Sampling. The Journal of Official
Statistics 24 (1), 79-97.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h4 id="applications">Applications&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>A good tutorial on the use of our package, including example data and R code is:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Khoury, R. (2020).
&lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.1017/S1537592719003864" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Hard-to-Survey Populations and Respondent-Driven Sampling: Expanding the Political Science
Toolbox&lt;/a>. Perspectives on Politics, 18(2), 509-526.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Khoury, R. (2020).
&lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.7910/DVN/XKOVUN" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Replication Data for: Hard-to-Survey Populations and Respondent-Driven Sampling: Expanding the Political Science
Toolbox&lt;/a>, Harvard Dataverse, V1.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul></description></item><item><title/><link>https://HPMRG.github.io/sspse/</link><pubDate>Wed, 24 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://HPMRG.github.io/sspse/</guid><description>&lt;img src="https://HPMRG.github.io/img/sspse_hl.png" align="left" width="250" height="250" style="padding:30px;" alt="RDS network"/>
&lt;h1 id="the-sspse-package">The &lt;code>sspse&lt;/code> package&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>This is an R package to implement successive sampling population size estimation (SS-PSE).&lt;/p>
&lt;p>SS-PSE is used to estimate the size of hidden populations using respondent-driven sampling (RDS) data. The package can implement SS-PSE,
visibility SS-PSE, and capture-recapture SS-PSE.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The package was developed by the
&lt;a href="https://HPMRG.github.io" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Hard-to-Reach Population Methods Research Group (HPMRG)&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;img src="https://HPMRG.github.io/img/fauxmadrona_recplot.jpeg" width = 900 alt="sspse banner"/>
&lt;h1 id="installation">Installation&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>The package is available on CRAN and can be installed using&lt;/p>
&lt;pre>&lt;code class="language-{r}">install.packages(&amp;quot;sspse&amp;quot;)
&lt;/code>&lt;/pre>
&lt;p>To install the latest development version from github, the best way it to use git to create a local copy and install it as usual from there. If
you just want to install it, you can also use:&lt;/p>
&lt;pre>&lt;code class="language-{r}"># If devtools is not installed:
# install.packages(&amp;quot;devtools&amp;quot;)
devtools::install_github(&amp;quot;HPMRG/sspse&amp;quot;)
&lt;/code>&lt;/pre>
&lt;h1 id="implementation">Implementation&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>Load package and example data&lt;/p>
&lt;pre>&lt;code>library(sspse)
data(fauxmadrona)
&lt;/code>&lt;/pre>
&lt;p>&lt;code>fauxmadrona&lt;/code> is a simulated RDS data set with no seed dependency, which is used to demonstrate RDS estimators. It has the format of an
&lt;code>rds.data.frame&lt;/code> and is a sample of size 500 with 10 seeds and 2 coupons from a population of size 1000. For the purpose of this example, we
will assume the population size is unknown and our goal is to estimate it.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>We can make a quick visualization of the recruitment chains, where the size of the node is proportional to the reported degree and the color
represents separate chains.&lt;/p>
&lt;pre>&lt;code class="language-{r}">reingold.tilford.plot(fauxmadrona,
vertex.label=NA,
vertex.size=&amp;quot;degree&amp;quot;,
show.legend=FALSE,
vertex.color=&amp;quot;seed&amp;quot;)
&lt;/code>&lt;/pre>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="reingold.tilford.png" alt="">&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="the-posteriorsize-function">The &lt;code>posteriorsize()&lt;/code> function&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>The function that will perform both the original and visibility variants of SS-PSE is called &lt;code>posteriorsize()&lt;/code>. It requires some prior knowledge
about the population size, $N$, which is usually expressed using the &lt;code>median.prior.size=&lt;/code> argument.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Although there are many options within the &lt;code>posteriorsize&lt;/code> function, most can be left at their default values unless you have a specific reason
to believe they should be set differently.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="original-ss-pse-example">Original SS-PSE example&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Set &lt;code>visibility=FALSE&lt;/code>. By default, 1000 samples will be drawn from the posterior distribution for $N$ using a burnin of 1000 and an interval of
10. This may take a few seconds to run.&lt;/p>
&lt;pre>&lt;code>fit1 &amp;lt;- posteriorsize(fauxmadrona,
median.prior.size=1000,
visibility=FALSE)
&lt;/code>&lt;/pre>
&lt;pre>&lt;code>## Using non-measurement error model with K = 14.
## Taken 1 samples...
## Taken 2 samples...
## Taken 4 samples...
...
## Taken 500 samples...
## Taken 1000 samples...
&lt;/code>&lt;/pre>
&lt;p>Plot the posterior distribution for $N$.&lt;/p>
&lt;pre>&lt;code>plot(fit1, type=&amp;quot;N&amp;quot;)
&lt;/code>&lt;/pre>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="fit.nme.png" alt="">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Create a table summary for the prior and posterior distributions for population size, specifying that we are interested in a 90% credible
interval for $N$.&lt;/p>
&lt;pre>&lt;code>summary(fit1, HPD.level = 0.9)
&lt;/code>&lt;/pre>
&lt;pre>&lt;code>## Summary of Population Size Estimation
## Mean Median Mode 25% 75% 90% 5% 95%
## Prior 1247 1000 680 748 1480 2240 583 2852
## Posterior 974 936 874 808 1100 1275 656 1400
&lt;/code>&lt;/pre>
&lt;h2 id="visibility-ss-pse-example">Visibility SS-PSE example&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Set &lt;code>visibility=TRUE&lt;/code>. Because of the measurement error model, this model will take a little longer to fit - perhaps a minute or so.&lt;/p>
&lt;pre>&lt;code>fit2 &amp;lt;- posteriorsize(fauxmadrona,
median.prior.size=1000,
visibility=TRUE)
&lt;/code>&lt;/pre>
&lt;pre>&lt;code>## Using a Exponentially Weighted Poisson measurement error model with K = 35.
## computing ...
## Taken 1 samples...
## Taken 2 samples...
...
## Taken 500 samples...
## Taken 1000 samples...
&lt;/code>&lt;/pre>
&lt;h2 id="summary-of-population-size-estimation">Summary of Population Size Estimation&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Plot the posterior distribution for $N$.&lt;/p>
&lt;pre>&lt;code>plot(fit2, type=&amp;quot;N&amp;quot;)
&lt;/code>&lt;/pre>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="fit.me.png" alt="">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Create a table summary for the prior and posterior distributions for population size, specifying that we are interested in a 90% credible
interval for $N$.&lt;/p>
&lt;pre>&lt;code>summary(fit2, HPD.level = 0.9)
&lt;/code>&lt;/pre>
&lt;pre>&lt;code>## Summary of Population Size Estimation
## Mean Median Mode 25% 75% 90% 5% 95%
## Prior 1247 1000 680 748 1480 2240 583 2852
## Posterior 1254 1100 913 858 1482 2016 621 2425
&lt;/code>&lt;/pre>
&lt;h1 id="resources">Resources&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>Please use the GitHub repository to report bugs or request features:
&lt;a href="https://https://github.com/HPMRG/sspse" target="_blank" rel="noopener">https://github.com/HPMRG/sspse&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;!-- A more detailed vignette with information on measurement error and diagnostics can be found here: [[link to katie's page]] -->
&lt;p>See the following papers for more information and examples:&lt;/p>
&lt;h4 id="statistical-methodology">Statistical Methodology&lt;/h4>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Handcock, Mark S.; Gile, Krista J. and Mar, Corinne M. (2014)
&lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.1214/14-ejs923" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Estimating Hidden Population Size using Respondent-Driven Sampling
Data&lt;/a>, &lt;em>Electronic Journal of Statistics&lt;/em>, 8(1):1491-1521.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Handcock, Mark S.; Gile, Krista J. and Mar, Corinne M. (2015)
&lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.1111/biom.12255" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Estimating the Size of Populations at High Risk for HIV using Respondent-Driven
Sampling Data&lt;/a>, &lt;em>Biometrics&lt;/em>, 71(1):258-266.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Kim, Brian J. and Handcock, Mark S. (2021)
&lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.1093/jssam/smz055" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Population Size Estimation Using Multiple Respondent-Driven Sampling
Surveys&lt;/a>, &lt;em>Journal of Survey Statistics and Methodology&lt;/em>, 9(1):94–120.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>McLaughlin, Katherine R.; Johnston, Lisa G.; Jakupi, Xhevat; Gexha-Bunjaku, Dafina; Deva, Edona and Handcock, Mark S.
(2023)
&lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.1214/23-AOAS1807" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Modeling the Visibility Distribution for Respondent-Driven Sampling with Application to Population Size Estimation&lt;/a>, &lt;em>Annals of Applied Statistics&lt;/em>.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h4 id="applications">Applications&lt;/h4>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Johnston, Lisa G., McLaughlin, Katherine R., El Rhilani, Houssine, Latifi, Amina, Toufik, Abdalla, Bennani, Aziza, Alami, Kamal, Elomari,
Boutaina, and Handcock, Mark S. (2015)
&lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.1097/EDE.0000000000000362" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Estimating the Size of Hidden Populations Using Respondent-driven Sampling Data: Case Examples from
Morocco&lt;/a>, &lt;em>Epidemiology&lt;/em>, 26(6):846-852.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Johnston, Lisa G., McLaughlin, Katherine R., Rouhani, Shada A., and Bartels, Susan A. (2017)
&lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jegh.2016.08.003" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Measuring a Hidden Population: A Novel Technique
to Estimate the Population Size of Women with Sexual Violence-Related Pregnancies in South Kivu Province, Democratic Republic of
Congo&lt;/a>, &lt;em>Journal of Epidemiology and Global Health&lt;/em>, 7(1):45-53.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>McLaughlin, Katherine R., Johnston, Lisa G., Gamble, Laura J., Grigoryan, Trdat, Papoyan, Arshak, and Grigoryan, Samvel (2019)
&lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.2196/12034" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Population
Size Estimations Among Hidden Populations Using Respondent-Driven Sampling Surveys: Case Studies From Armenia&lt;/a>,
&lt;em>JMIR Public Health and Surveillance&lt;/em>, 5(1):e12034.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Johnston, Lisa G., McLaughlin, Katherine R., Gios, Lorenzo, Cordioli, Maddalena, Staneková, Danica V.,Blondeel, Karel, Toskin, Igor,
Mirandola, Massimo, and The SIALON II Network (2021)
&lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.1093/eurpub/ckab148" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Populations size estimations using SS-PSE among MSM in four European cities: how many
MSM are living with HIV?&lt;/a>, &lt;em>European Journal of Public Health&lt;/em>, 31(6):1129–1136.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul></description></item><item><title>Citation</title><link>https://HPMRG.github.io/rdsanalyst/citation/</link><pubDate>Wed, 24 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://HPMRG.github.io/rdsanalyst/citation/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="rds-analyst-citation-information">RDS Analyst citation information&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>If you are using &lt;u>RDS Analyst&lt;/u> for research that will be published, we request that you acknowledge this with the following citation:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Mark S. Handcock, Ian E. Fellows, Krista J. Gile (2022) RDS Analyst:
Software for the Analysis of Respondent-Driven Sampling Data, Version
0.72, URL
&lt;a href="https://hpmrg.org" target="_blank" rel="noopener">https://hpmrg.org&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>A BibTeX entry for LaTeX users is&lt;/p>
&lt;pre>&lt;code class="language-diff">+@Manual{RDSA,
+ title = {RDS Analyst: Software for the Analysis of Respondent-Driven Sampling Data},
+ author = {Mark S. Handcock and Ian E. Fellows and Krista J. Gile},
+ year = {2022},
+ note = {Version 0.72},
+ address = {Los Angeles, CA},
+ url = {https://hpmrg.org},
+}@@
&lt;/code>&lt;/pre>
&lt;p>We have invested a lot of time and effort in creating &lt;u>RDS Analyst&lt;/u> for use by other researchers. Please cite it in all papers where it is
used.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="citing-the-component-packages-of-urds-analystu-eg-rds-or-deducerrdsanalyst">Citing the component packages of &lt;u>RDS Analyst&lt;/u> (e.g., &lt;code>RDS&lt;/code> or &lt;code>DeducerRDSAnalyst&lt;/code>)&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>To cite the individual R packages (e.g., &lt;code>RDS&lt;/code> or &lt;code>DeducerRDSAnalyst&lt;/code>) please use the information given by their individual citation function
calls. For example, at the &lt;code>R&lt;/code> Console window type:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;code>citation(package=&amp;quot;RDS&amp;quot;)&lt;/code>&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="citing-udeduceru">Citing &lt;u>Deducer&lt;/u>&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>&lt;u>RDS Analyst&lt;/u> is built on the graphical user interface and capabilities of &lt;u>Deducer&lt;/u>. To cite &lt;u>Deducer&lt;/u>, see
&lt;a href="https://cran.r-project.org/web/packages/Deducer/citation.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener">here&lt;/a>.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Migrating my website to Hugo + Academic</title><link>https://HPMRG.github.io/post/migrating/</link><pubDate>Wed, 20 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://HPMRG.github.io/post/migrating/</guid><description>&lt;p>After many years with a hand written website in HTML, I moved to using the
&lt;a href="https://gohugo.io/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Hugo&lt;/a> framework with the
&lt;a href="https://sourcethemes.com/academic/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Academic theme&lt;/a>.
The motivation for this is the work of
&lt;a href="https://www.statslab.cam.ac.uk/~qz280/post/migrating/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Qingyuan Zhao&lt;/a> who deserved the credit for both creating the template and also publishing it so that others can benefit from it. Thank you, Qingyuan Zhao!&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="the-hugo-framework-with-the-academic-theme">The Hugo framework with the Academic theme&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Based on Qingyuan&amp;rsquo;s work, I decided to use Hugo as it is an efficient language expressing
the best aspects of markdown. The Academic theme for Hugo is well suited for
the websites of academic researchers.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It helps to have Hugo installed locally as you can compile the website and see what you will get. Installing Hugo in Mac OS X is
straightforward with
&lt;a href="https://brew.sh/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">homebrew&lt;/a>. Simply run&lt;/p>
&lt;pre>&lt;code class="language-sh">brew install hugo
&lt;/code>&lt;/pre>
&lt;h3 id="creating-a-local-website">Creating a local website&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>First, clone my repository or Qingyuan&amp;rsquo;s. I put mine in &amp;ldquo;handcock.github.io&amp;rdquo;. Then rename it to &amp;lt;git hub ID&amp;gt;.github.io&lt;/p>
&lt;p>You can preview the website by running&lt;/p>
&lt;pre>&lt;code class="language-sh">hugo server --baseURL https://localhost:1313/
&lt;/code>&lt;/pre>
&lt;p>from the website directory (e.g., &amp;ldquo;handcock.github.io&amp;rdquo;). This builds the website and creates a
local web server to host it. It generates a link (the default is
&lt;a href="https://localhost:1313/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">https://localhost:1313/&lt;/a>)
which can be pasted into a web browser. In the background, the hugo
server also detects any change to the content and updates the website
automatically.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="making-it-your-website">Making it your website&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>The files are all writen as text files in markdown. The &lt;code>content&lt;/code> sub-folder contains all the Markdown files
for website content.&lt;/p>
&lt;pre>&lt;code class="language-text">├── content
│   ├── authors
│   ├── featured
│   ├── group
│   ├── home
│   ├── post
│   ├── project
│   ├── publication
│   ├── research
│   ├── talk
│   └── teaching
&lt;/code>&lt;/pre>
&lt;p>Most of its sub-directories correspond to a
section of my webpage (take a look at it); in particular, &lt;code>home&lt;/code> corresponds to the
homepage of your website. Another unique folder is the &lt;code>authors&lt;/code>,
which contains basic information about the website owner and all other
authors (not needed for a personal website). The &lt;code>publication&lt;/code> corresponds to each of my publications.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Basically, you will edit the text files in each of these sub-directiries to change them to ones that are for you (as now they are all for me!).&lt;/p>
&lt;p>See
&lt;a href="https://sourcethemes.com/academic/docs/get-started/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">its documentation&lt;/a> for more information.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="creating-a-public-website">Creating a public website&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Commit your website as a repository on github (with &amp;lt;git hub ID&amp;gt;.github.io as a name).&lt;/p>
&lt;p>After successfully committed, go to your repository and click on the “Settings” on the top right, then scroll down to the Github Pages section.
Then click on the published link.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>CCPR</title><link>https://HPMRG.github.io/research/ccpr/</link><pubDate>Tue, 19 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://HPMRG.github.io/research/ccpr/</guid><description>&lt;p>I am an affiliate of the
&lt;a href="https://www.ccpr.ucla.edu/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">California Center for Population Research&lt;/a> at UCLA.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>COVID-19</title><link>https://HPMRG.github.io/project/covid-19/</link><pubDate>Fri, 24 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://HPMRG.github.io/project/covid-19/</guid><description/></item><item><title/><link>https://HPMRG.github.io/featured/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://HPMRG.github.io/featured/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Software</title><link>https://HPMRG.github.io/software/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://HPMRG.github.io/software/</guid><description>&lt;ul>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>
&lt;a href="https://HPMRG.github.io/rdsanalyst" target="_blank" rel="noopener">RDS Analyst&lt;/a> is a software
package for the analysis of Respondent-driven sampling (RDS) data that
implements recent advances in statistical methods. RDS Analyst has an
easy-to-use graphical user interface to the powerful and sophisticated
capabilities of the computer package R. It provides a comprehensive
framework for working with RDS data, including tools for sample and
population estimations, testing, confidence intervals and sensitivity
analysis.
&lt;br>
For more information, click
&lt;a href="https://HPMRG.github.io/rdsanalyst" target="_blank" rel="noopener">here&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>
&lt;a href="https://HPMRG.github.io/sspse" target="_blank" rel="noopener">sspse&lt;/a>: an
&lt;a href="https://www.r-project.org/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">R&lt;/a> software package
for estimating the population size of a hidden population based on Respondent Driven Sampling data.
The CRAN
&lt;a href="https://cran.r-project.org/web/packages/sspse" target="_blank" rel="noopener">manual&lt;/a> is very detailed.
&lt;br>
For more information, click
&lt;a href="https://HPMRG.github.io/sspse" target="_blank" rel="noopener">here&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>
&lt;a href="https://HPMRG.github.io/rds" target="_blank" rel="noopener">RDS&lt;/a>: an
&lt;a href="https://www.r-project.org/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">R&lt;/a> software package
for carrying out estimation with data collected using
Respondent-Driven Sampling. The CRAN
&lt;a href="https://cran.r-project.org/web/packages/RDS" target="_blank" rel="noopener">manual&lt;/a> is very detailed.
&lt;br>
For more information, click
&lt;a href="https://HPMRG.github.io/rds" target="_blank" rel="noopener">here&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul></description></item></channel></rss>