<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="https://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Mark S. Handcock</title><link>https://HPMRG.github.io/author/</link><atom:link href="https://HPMRG.github.io/author/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><description>Mark S. Handcock</description><generator>Source Themes Academic (https://sourcethemes.com/academic/)</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>2022</copyright><image><url>https://HPMRG.github.io/images/logo_hu7ac5a2aa8fa12518fd9ab7ceccb2a15e_77341_300x300_fit_lanczos_3.png</url><title>Mark S. Handcock</title><link>https://HPMRG.github.io/author/</link></image><item><title/><link>https://HPMRG.github.io/author/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://HPMRG.github.io/author/</guid><description>&lt;img src="https://HPMRG.github.io/img/avatar.jpg" align="right" width="250" height="250" alt="RDS network"/>
&lt;p>The Hard-to-Reach Population Methods Research Group (HPMRG) focuses on developing statistical methodology to help improve understanding of
hard-to-reach or otherwise &amp;ldquo;hidden&amp;rdquo; populations.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>These populations are characterized by the difficulty in survey sampling from them using standard probability methods. Typically, a sampling
frame for the target population is not available, and its members are rare or stigmatized in the larger population so that it is prohibitively
expensive to contact them through the available frames. Examples of such populations in a behavioral and social setting include injection drug
users, men who have sex with men, and female sex workers. Examples in an economic setting include unregulated workers and the self-employed.
Hard-to-reach populations in the US and elsewhere are under-served by current sampling methodologies mainly due to the lack of practical
alternatives to address these methodological difficulties.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>See the menu bar at the top for inormation about &lt;span style="color:blue">RDS Analyst&lt;/span> software&lt;/p>
&lt;!-- &lt;img src="https://HPMRG.github.io/img/logo.png" align="left" width="400" height="400" alt="RDS network"/> --></description></item><item><title>Mark S. Handcock</title><link>https://HPMRG.github.io/author/mark-s.-handcock/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://HPMRG.github.io/author/mark-s.-handcock/</guid><description>&lt;p>I am a statistician whose research involves methodological development, and is based largely on motivation from questions in the social sciences, social epidemiology and environmetrics.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>My recent work is on statistical models for social networks, network inference, the development of statistical methodology for the collection and analysis of social network data, surveying of hard-to-reach populations, spatial processes and demography.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>